<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Blue Room Challenge (+Curses)</name>
    <directory>blue room challenge</directory>
    <id>2724537570</id>
    <description>[h1]Challenges[/h1]

This mod adds 6 custom challenges.

[b][u]Blue Room Challenge[/u][/b]

Play as Blue Baby and go fight yourself in the Chest.

Between each room is a hidden blue room. Doorways will glow blue to alert you to their presence. Once you clear and leave a blue room, it will disappear.

A random boss pool item and Book of Revelations will spawn in the first room.

[b][u]Blue Room Challenge (Cursed)[/u][/b]

Each blue room is covered in a layer of cursed mist that temporarily reduces you to base items and stats.

[b][u]Blue Room Challenge (Hush)[/u][/b]

This is the same as the normal challenge, but you're headed to Hush.

[b][u]Dark Room Challenge[/u][/b]

Tainted Judas wants in on the fun. Fight your way to The Lamb in the Dark Room.

All of the Blue Room Challenge rules apply here. Additionally, you'll be surrounded in a cone of complete darkness.

Dark Arts can help get you out of tricky situations.

A random boss pool item and Satanic Bible will spawn in the first room.

[b][u]Dark Room Challenge (Cursed)[/u][/b]

Can you deal with the cone of darkness and cursed mist?

[b][u]Dark Room Challenge (Hush)[/u][/b]

This is the same as the normal challenge, but you're headed to Hush.

[h1]Curses[/h1]

This mod has been updated with the following curses which are available in every mode. Mod Config Menu can be used to change how often they show up.

[b][u]Curse of Blue Rooms![/u][/b]

This is what the normal challenges use.

[b][u]Curse of Blue Rooms!![/u][/b]

This is what the cursed challenges use.

[b][u]Curse of Pitch Black![/u][/b]

This is the cone of darkness surrounding Tainted Judas in his challenges.

[h1]Known Issues[/h1]

If you enter a blue room from a large room, clear the blue room, and exit via the entrance door: you might find yourself against the correct wall, but at the wrong door slot. This is a bug with the game. The same thing happens in a normal run with the blue key.

There is a blue room glow for secret rooms, but it's hard to see in normally lit rooms.

The icon for the custom curses will either show Curse of the Giant or nothing. The text should be correct though.

After installing the latest update, you might need to restart the game for it to properly pick up the curses.

The Hush challenges will show the Mom's Heart icon as the ending boss.</description>
    <version>1.13</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Hazards"/>
    <tag id="Challenges"/>
</metadata>
